Toggle navigation[OneGreenPlanet](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/)

    * [
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/vegancookbooks)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/vegan-recipe/strawberry-shortcake-vegan/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/vegan-recipe/strawberry-shortcake-vegan/)
        
        [Strawberry Shortcake \[Vegan\]](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/vegan-recipe/strawberry-shortcake-vegan/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/vegan-recipe/almond-flour-strawberry-shortcake-vegan-gluten-free/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/vegan-recipe/almond-flour-strawberry-shortcake-vegan-gluten-free/)
        
        [Almond Flour Strawberry Shortcake \[Vegan, Gluten-Free\]](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/vegan-recipe/almond-flour-strawberry-shortcake-vegan-gluten-free/)

    * [
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/vegancookbooks)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/10-delicious-and-nutritious-natural-recipes-to-reduce-inflammation-from-gerd/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/10-delicious-and-nutritious-natural-recipes-to-reduce-inflammation-from-gerd/)
        
        [10 Delicious and Nutritious Natural Recipes to Reduce Inflammation from GERD](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/10-delicious-and-nutritious-natural-recipes-to-reduce-inflammation-from-gerd/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/vegan-food/15-recipes-for-vegan-spring-rolls/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/vegan-food/15-recipes-for-vegan-spring-rolls/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/weekly-top-news-vermont-is-holding-oil-companies-accountable-plastic-toy-bricks-are-creating-microplastic-pollution-redditor-asks-how-to-support-vegan-girlfriend-and-more/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/weekly-top-news-vermont-is-holding-oil-companies-accountable-plastic-toy-bricks-are-creating-microplastic-pollution-redditor-asks-how-to-support-vegan-girlfriend-and-more/)
        
        [Weekly Top News: Vermont is Holding Oil Companies Accountable, Plastic Toy Bricks are Creating Microplastic Pollution, Redditor Asks How to Support Vegan Girlfriend, and More!](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/weekly-top-news-vermont-is-holding-oil-companies-accountable-plastic-toy-bricks-are-creating-microplastic-pollution-redditor-asks-how-to-support-vegan-girlfriend-and-more/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/weekly-top-animal-and-video-news-surfboard-stealing-otter-returns-to-santa-cruz-animal-testing-company-pays-historic-fine-african-penguins-face-dire-future-and-more/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/weekly-top-animal-and-video-news-surfboard-stealing-otter-returns-to-santa-cruz-animal-testing-company-pays-historic-fine-african-penguins-face-dire-future-and-more/)
        
        [Weekly Top Animal and Video News: Surfboard-Stealing Otter Returns to Santa Cruz, Animal Testing Company Pays Historic Fine, African Penguins Face Dire Future, and More!](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/weekly-top-animal-and-video-news-surfboard-stealing-otter-returns-to-santa-cruz-animal-testing-company-pays-historic-fine-african-penguins-face-dire-future-and-more/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/watch-this-dog-get-excited-when-dad-returns-home/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/watch-this-dog-get-excited-when-dad-returns-home/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/jack-russell-charms-the-internet-with-adorable-delivery-encounter/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/jack-russell-charms-the-internet-with-adorable-delivery-encounter/)
        
        [Jack Russell Charms the Internet with Adorable Delivery Encounter](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/jack-russell-charms-the-internet-with-adorable-delivery-encounter/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/adorable-concertgoer-steals-the-spotlight/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/adorable-concertgoer-steals-the-spotlight/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/new-airline-provides-luxury-air-travel-for-dogs-and-their-humans/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/new-airline-provides-luxury-air-travel-for-dogs-and-their-humans/)
        
        [New Airline Provides Luxury Air Travel for Dogs and Their Humans](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/new-airline-provides-luxury-air-travel-for-dogs-and-their-humans/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/environment/7-upcoming-environmental-grants-to-apply-for/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/environment/7-upcoming-environmental-grants-to-apply-for/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/environment/10-successful-beach-cleanup-projects-around-the-world/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/environment/10-successful-beach-cleanup-projects-around-the-world/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/environment/exploring-12-of-the-worlds-largest-landfills-and-their-impact-on-waste-management/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/environment/exploring-12-of-the-worlds-largest-landfills-and-their-impact-on-waste-management/)
        
        [Exploring 12 of the World’s Largest Landfills and Their Impact on Waste Management](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/environment/exploring-12-of-the-worlds-largest-landfills-and-their-impact-on-waste-management/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/environment/10-inspiring-examples-of-industrial-site-remediation/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/environment/10-inspiring-examples-of-industrial-site-remediation/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/environment/global-warming-over-the-past-10-years-a-timeline-of-events-and-impacts/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/environment/global-warming-over-the-past-10-years-a-timeline-of-events-and-impacts/)
        
        [Global Warming Over the Past 10 Years: A Timeline of Events and Impacts](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/environment/global-warming-over-the-past-10-years-a-timeline-of-events-and-impacts/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/environment/8-ways-amazon-is-contributing-to-environmental-destruction/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/environment/8-ways-amazon-is-contributing-to-environmental-destruction/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/pros-and-cons-of-adopting-a-bunny-rabbit-easter/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/pros-and-cons-of-adopting-a-bunny-rabbit-easter/)
        
        [Thinking About Adopting a Bunny This Easter? Here’s Why You Need to Stop Right Now!](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/pros-and-cons-of-adopting-a-bunny-rabbit-easter/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/impact-of-keeping-polar-bears-in-zoos/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/impact-of-keeping-polar-bears-in-zoos/)
        
        [What Keeping Polar Bears in Zoos and Aquariums Does to These Animals Will Shock You](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/impact-of-keeping-polar-bears-in-zoos/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/simple-reasons-you-should-spay-or-neuter-your-pet/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/simple-reasons-you-should-spay-or-neuter-your-pet/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/this-cat-mama-is-so-proud-of-her-new-kittens/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/this-cat-mama-is-so-proud-of-her-new-kittens/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/this-adopted-doberman-came-with-a-surprise/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/this-adopted-doberman-came-with-a-surprise/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/blue-the-sick-dog-found-covered-in-spray-paint-rescued/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/blue-the-sick-dog-found-covered-in-spray-paint-rescued/)

    * [
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/vegancookbooks)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/12-ways-to-keep-your-gut-and-digestive-system-in-tip-top-shape/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/12-ways-to-keep-your-gut-and-digestive-system-in-tip-top-shape/)
        
        [12 Ways to Keep Your Gut and Digestive System in Tip-Top Shape](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/12-ways-to-keep-your-gut-and-digestive-system-in-tip-top-shape/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/10-delicious-and-nutritious-natural-recipes-to-reduce-inflammation-from-gerd/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/10-delicious-and-nutritious-natural-recipes-to-reduce-inflammation-from-gerd/)
        
        [10 Delicious and Nutritious Natural Recipes to Reduce Inflammation from GERD](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/10-delicious-and-nutritious-natural-recipes-to-reduce-inflammation-from-gerd/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/8-natural-plant-based-recipes-to-alkalize-your-body-and-restore-ph-balance-naturally/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/8-natural-plant-based-recipes-to-alkalize-your-body-and-restore-ph-balance-naturally/)
        
        [8 Natural Plant-Based Recipes to Alkalize Your Body and Restore pH Balance Naturally](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/8-natural-plant-based-recipes-to-alkalize-your-body-and-restore-ph-balance-naturally/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/foods-that-lower-your-blood-sugar-quickly/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/foods-that-lower-your-blood-sugar-quickly/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/social-frailty-empowering-older-adults-through-connection-and-support/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/social-frailty-empowering-older-adults-through-connection-and-support/)
        
        [Social Frailty: Empowering Older Adults through Connection and Support](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/social-frailty-empowering-older-adults-through-connection-and-support/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/human-interest/global-waters-exceed-safe-pfa-levels-new-study-reveals/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/human-interest/global-waters-exceed-safe-pfa-levels-new-study-reveals/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/human-interest/10-animal-vegan-and-sustainability-centered-organizations-supporting-minorites/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/human-interest/10-animal-vegan-and-sustainability-centered-organizations-supporting-minorites/)
        
        [10 Animal, Vegan, and Sustainability Centered Organizations Supporting Minorites](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/human-interest/10-animal-vegan-and-sustainability-centered-organizations-supporting-minorites/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/human-interest/10-disgusting-facts-about-meat-production-that-will-make-you-rethink-your-diet/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/human-interest/10-disgusting-facts-about-meat-production-that-will-make-you-rethink-your-diet/)
        
        [10 Disgusting Facts About Meat Production That Will Make You Rethink Your Diet](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/human-interest/10-disgusting-facts-about-meat-production-that-will-make-you-rethink-your-diet/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/human-interest/10-reasons-to-ditch-bottled-water-health-environmental-and-economic-concerns/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/human-interest/10-reasons-to-ditch-bottled-water-health-environmental-and-economic-concerns/)
        
        [10 Reasons to Ditch Bottled Water: Health, Environmental, and Economic Concerns](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/human-interest/10-reasons-to-ditch-bottled-water-health-environmental-and-economic-concerns/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/human-interest/how-proximity-to-oil-and-gas-sites-are-linked-to-maternal-health-risks-and-childhood-leukemia/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/human-interest/how-proximity-to-oil-and-gas-sites-are-linked-to-maternal-health-risks-and-childhood-leukemia/)
        
        [How Proximity to Oil and Gas Sites Are Linked to Maternal Health Risks and Childhood Leukemia](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/human-interest/how-proximity-to-oil-and-gas-sites-are-linked-to-maternal-health-risks-and-childhood-leukemia/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/environment/climate-change-forces-four-native-groups-to-relocate/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/environment/climate-change-forces-four-native-groups-to-relocate/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/10-products-for-joint-pain-and-arthritis-in-animal-companions/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/10-products-for-joint-pain-and-arthritis-in-animal-companions/)
        
        [10 Products for Joint Pain and Arthritis in Animal Companions](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/10-products-for-joint-pain-and-arthritis-in-animal-companions/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/farm-bill-would-erase-decades-of-meaningful-progress-for-humane-treatment-of-farm-animals/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/farm-bill-would-erase-decades-of-meaningful-progress-for-humane-treatment-of-farm-animals/)
        
        [Farm Bill Would Erase Decades of Meaningful Progress for Humane Treatment of Farm Animals](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/farm-bill-would-erase-decades-of-meaningful-progress-for-humane-treatment-of-farm-animals/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/10-eco-friendly-litters/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/10-eco-friendly-litters/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/five-times-animals-saved-their-humans-life-with-last-minute-critical-thinking/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/five-times-animals-saved-their-humans-life-with-last-minute-critical-thinking/)
        
        [Five Times Animals Saved Their Human’s Life with Last Minute Critical Thinking](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/five-times-animals-saved-their-humans-life-with-last-minute-critical-thinking/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/may-2024-animal-law-updates-the-gambit-and-the-other-shoe/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/may-2024-animal-law-updates-the-gambit-and-the-other-shoe/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/10-must-have-first-aid-kits-and-supplies-for-animal-companions/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/10-must-have-first-aid-kits-and-supplies-for-animal-companions/)
        
        [10 MUST HAVE First Aid Kits and Supplies for Animal Companions](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animals/10-must-have-first-aid-kits-and-supplies-for-animal-companions/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/vegan-food/how-to-make-vegan-fried-chicken/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/vegan-food/how-to-make-vegan-fried-chicken/)
        
        [How to Make Vegan Fried ‘Chicken’ \[Video\]](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/vegan-food/how-to-make-vegan-fried-chicken/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/team-rescues-dogs-living-in-school/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/team-rescues-dogs-living-in-school/)
        
        [Dedicated Team Rescues 2 Dogs Who Were Living in an Abandoned School! \[Video\]](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/team-rescues-dogs-living-in-school/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/homeless-dog-and-puppies-in-heavy-rainstorm/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/homeless-dog-and-puppies-in-heavy-rainstorm/)
        
        [Watch the Rescue of a Homeless Dog and 8 Puppies in a Heavy Rainstorm! \[Video\]](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/homeless-dog-and-puppies-in-heavy-rainstorm/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/amazing-pilot-flies-pups-from-crowded-shelters-to-their-forever-homes-video/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/amazing-pilot-flies-pups-from-crowded-shelters-to-their-forever-homes-video/)
        
        [Amazing Pilot Flies Pups from Crowded Shelters to Their Forever Homes! \[Video\]](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/amazing-pilot-flies-pups-from-crowded-shelters-to-their-forever-homes-video/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/youve-never-seen-a-puppy-and-baby-so-madly-in-love/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/youve-never-seen-a-puppy-and-baby-so-madly-in-love/)
        
        [Puppy and Baby are So Madly in Love… It Hurts to Watch! \[Video\]](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/youve-never-seen-a-puppy-and-baby-so-madly-in-love/)

        [](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/orangutan-trying-stop-bulldozer-destroying-home/)[
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/orangutan-trying-stop-bulldozer-destroying-home/)
        
        [Orangutan Desperately Trying to Stop a Bulldozer From Destroying His Home Is a Wake Up Call For Us All \[Video\]](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/orangutan-trying-stop-bulldozer-destroying-home/)
        
* [About](javascript:void(0);)
    
    OneGreenPlanet Cookbooks
    ------------------------
    
    * [
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/product/better-burgers-make-delicious-nutrient-rich-burgers-without-the-meat/)
        
        [BETTER BURGERS: Make Delicious Nutrient-Rich Burgers Without The Meat](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/product/better-burgers-make-delicious-nutrient-rich-burgers-without-the-meat/)
        
    * [
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/product/summer-plant-based-recipe-cookbook/)
        
        [SUMMER: Stunning Plant-Based Recipes to Enjoy All Season When the Sun's Out](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/product/summer-plant-based-recipe-cookbook/)
        
    * [
        
        ](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/product/alive-detox-vegan-cookbook/)

* [Shop](javascript:void(0);)
    
    OneGreenPlanet Newsletter
    -------------------------
    
     Subscribe
    
    Get your favorite articles delivered right to your inbox!
    
    [Sign up](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/newsletter-2/) for daily news from OneGreenPlanet

No products in the cart.

* * Toggle navigation
    * [
        
        ](#)

* 
* #### Search By Post Type
    
    * [ ] Posts
    * [ ] Recipes
    * [ ] Videos
* #### Search By Post Category
    
    * [ ] Allergies
    * [ ] Animals
    * [ ] Autoimmune Health
    * [ ] Baking
    * [ ] Budget Friendly Guides
    * [ ] Burger
    * [ ] Buzz
    * [ ] Cheese
    * [ ] Collections
    * [ ] Contest Winner
    * [ ] Dairy
    * [ ] Earth
    * [ ] Eating Out Guides
    * [ ] Eggs
    * [ ] Flavor
    * [ ] Food
    * [ ] Grow / Harvest
    * [ ] Guides
    * [ ] Gut Health
    * [ ] Health
    * [ ] Heart Health
    * [ ] Holiday and Festival Guides
    * [ ] Human Interest
    * [ ] Ingredient Guides
    * [ ] International Cooking Guides
    * [ ] Life
    * [ ] Mental Health & Wellness
    * [ ] N/A
    * [ ] N/A
    * [ ] N/A
    * [ ] n/a
    * [ ] N/A
    * [ ] N/A
    * [ ] N/A
    * [ ] N/A
    * [ ] Pet Food
    * [ ] Plant-Based Nutrition
    * [ ] Plant-Based Protein Guides
    * [ ] Plant-Based Recipe Roundups
    * [ ] Plant-Based Strength
    * [ ] Popular Trends
    * [ ] Products
    * [ ] Quick & Easy
    * [ ] Recipes
    * [ ] Seasonal
    * [ ] Take Action! Sign These Petitions
    * [ ] Tips & Hacks
    * [ ] Tofu
    * [ ] Uncategorized
    * [ ] Vegetable
    * [ ] Videos
    * [ ] Whole Foods

    * 

        [How to Make Healthy, Organic, Homemade Ketchup (No Added Sugar!)](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/vegan-food/how-to-make-sugar-free-organic-ketchup/)
        
    * 

        [Heartbreaking Moment Pit Bull Realized She Had Been Abandoned in a Shelter is a Lesson for all Pet Parents \[Video\]](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/pit-bull-realized-she-had-been-abandoned/)
        
    * 

        [Bloated on a Vegan Diet? Here’s Why and How to Improve Your Digestion](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/how-to-improve-digestion/)
        
    * 

        [Cute Orphaned Baby Elephant and Giraffe are The Best of Friends \[Video\]](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/cute-orphaned-baby-elephant-and-giraffe-are-the-best-of-friends/)
        
    * 

        [Casein: The Disturbing Connection Between This Dairy Protein and Your Health](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/casein-dairy-protein-and-your-health/)
        
    * 

        [3-Legged Homeless Dog Tried to Adopt Her Own Family by Camping Out in a Box \[Video\]](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/homeless-chihuahua-who-lived-in-box-gets-rescued/)
        
* [Products](javascript:void(0);)

* Categories

* Newsletter
    
* [About](javascript:void(0);)

#### Trending

* 

    [How to Make Healthy, Organic, Homemade Ketchup (No Added Sugar!)](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/vegan-food/how-to-make-sugar-free-organic-ketchup/)
    
* 

    [Heartbreaking Moment Pit Bull Realized She Had Been Abandoned in a Shelter is a Lesson for all Pet Parents \[Video\]](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/pit-bull-realized-she-had-been-abandoned/)
    
* 

    [Bloated on a Vegan Diet? Here’s Why and How to Improve Your Digestion](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/how-to-improve-digestion/)
    
* 

    [Cute Orphaned Baby Elephant and Giraffe are The Best of Friends \[Video\]](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/news/cute-orphaned-baby-elephant-and-giraffe-are-the-best-of-friends/)
    
* 

    [Casein: The Disturbing Connection Between This Dairy Protein and Your Health](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/natural-health/casein-dairy-protein-and-your-health/)
    
* 

    [3-Legged Homeless Dog Tried to Adopt Her Own Family by Camping Out in a Box \[Video\]](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/homeless-chihuahua-who-lived-in-box-gets-rescued/)
    
* 

* 

    [This Pit Bull Was Given to a Neighbor Because She Wasn’t a ‘Good Fit’ But They Abandoned Her! \[Video\]](https://www.onegreenplanet.org/animalsandnature/pit-bull-given-neighbor-wasnt-good-fit-abandoned/)
    
* 

×

* 
* #### Search By Post Type
    
    * [ ] Posts
    * [ ] Recipes
    * [ ] Videos
* #### Search By Post Category
    
    * [ ] Allergies
    * [ ] Animals
    * [ ] Autoimmune Health
    * [ ] Baking
    * [ ] Budget Friendly Guides
    * [ ] Burger
    * [ ] Buzz
    * [ ] Cheese
    * [ ] Collections
    * [ ] Contest Winner
    * [ ] Dairy
    * [ ] Earth
    * [ ] Eating Out Guides
    * [ ] Eggs
    * [ ] Flavor
    * [ ] Food
    * [ ] Grow / Harvest
    * [ ] Guides
    * [ ] Gut Health
    * [ ] Health
    * [ ] Heart Health
    * [ ] Holiday and Festival Guides
    * [ ] Human Interest
    * [ ] Ingredient Guides
    * [ ] International Cooking Guides
    * [ ] Life
    * [ ] Mental Health & Wellness
    * [ ] N/A
    * [ ] N/A
    * [ ] N/A
    * [ ] n/a
    * [ ] N/A
    * [ ] N/A
    * [ ] N/A
    * [ ] N/A
    * [ ] Pet Food
    * [ ] Plant-Based Nutrition
    * [ ] Plant-Based Protein Guides
    * [ ] Plant-Based Recipe Roundups
    * [ ] Plant-Based Strength
    * [ ] Popular Trends
    * [ ] Products
    * [ ] Quick & Easy
    * [ ] Recipes
    * [ ] Seasonal
    * [ ] Take Action! Sign These Petitions
    * [ ] Tips & Hacks
    * [ ] Tofu
    * [ ] Uncategorized
    * [ ] Vegetable
    * [ ] Videos
    * [ ] Whole Foods

#### Get thousands of vegan, allergy-friendly recipes in the palm of your hands today!

X

#### Get your favorite articles delivered right to your inbox!

X

Privacy Policy
==============

The privacy of our visitors is very important to us. This privacy policy describes what types of information we receive and collect when you use and visit OneGreenPlanet.org and how we safeguard your information.

**Information Collected**

_Personally Identifiable Information_

Personally-identifiable information is information that identifies or can be used to identify a user as a specific individual, such as a name, email address, mailing address and phone number.

We collect personally-identifiable information about you only if you voluntarily provide that information when you fill out a form, submit an article or recipe, enter a contest or giveaway, submit a product review or post a comment on this site.

_Non-Personally Identifiable Information_

Non-personally identifiable information includes demographic information (such as age, gender, city or state) and a user’s click stream information.  We collect non-personally identifiable information in the following instances:

_Log Files_

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files.  The information in the log files include  non-personally identifiable information that your browser automatically sends whenever you visit OneGreenPlanet.org, including your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP, browser type, browser language, date and time of the request.

_Cookies and web beacons_

Cookies are small text files that are stored within a browser. They are accessed and recorded by the web site visited and by the companies that show ads on that site to enable them to recognize the same browser or user. Web beacons are small electronic files that allow a web site to count users who have visited that page or to access certain cookies.  The OneGreenPlanet.org site uses web beacons in order to analyze the performance and usefulness of our site.

We may use services provided by third parties like [Google Analytics](https://www.google.com/analytics), [Quantcast](https://www.quantcast.com/) and [Chartbeat](https://chartbeat.com/) to track usage on our site. In addition, we have implemented social sharing buttons on OneGreenPlanet.org, so you can easily “Like” or share our content via, [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/), [Twitter](https://twitter.com/), [Pinterest](https://www.pinterest.com/), [Linkedin](https://www.linkedin.com/), [StumbleUpon](https://www.stumbleupon.com/), [Google+](https://plus.google.com/), [Reddit](https://www.reddit.com/), etc. These third parties have their own privacy policies, which you can view through their respective websites. Some of these third parties store cookies in your browser.

We also use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: [https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt\_out.asp](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

We serve [Ad Council PSAs](https://www.adcouncil.org/) that involves the uses of Google’s DART cookies to serve ads on OneGreenPlanet.org. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – [https://www.google.com/privacy\_ads.html](https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

One Green Planet has no access to or control over these cookies used by third parties. The OneGreenPlanet.org privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers, services or web sites.

You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to log in to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

**Information use**

_Personally-Identifiable Information_

We use the personally-identifiable information you provide through the OneGreenPlanet.org site to respond to your inquiries and requests and to keep accurate records concerning the services you are requesting through OneGreenPlanet.org, including but not limited to improving our website based on the information and feedback we receive from you, administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature, send you information, respond to inquiries and/or other requests or questions, etc.

_Non-Personally Identifiable Information_

We uses non-personally identifiable information in aggregated form to help us measure the OneGreenPlanet.org site’s performance and effectiveness and to improve its usefulness.

**Information Disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to your personally identifiable information to third parties without your consent. This does not include selected partners, vendors, agents or other third parties, who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, provide products or services you have requested, or when we have your permission.  We may share information about you if One Green Planet LLC is acquired or merged with another company. We may also share information in the event that we are asked to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims, or as otherwise permitted by law.

**User Rights**

1\. You May Decline to Provide Information. You may decline to submit personal information and/or disable webpage cookies.

2\. Effect of Declining to Provide Information. If you decline to submit personal information or any portion thereof, you may experience materially reduced services quality.

3\. You May Request Deletion of Personal Information. You may request that One Green Planet delete your own personal information. However, you acknowledge and agree that doing so shall relieve and release One Green Planet from any liability, obligation, claim, or other damages related to or arising from said personal information. To request deletion of personal information, send an email to Team@onegreenplanet.org

4\. No Sensitive Information. You acknowledge and agree that the information you are providing to One Green Planet is not sensitive in nature (i.e., is not personal information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, etc.)

5\. ADDITIONAL DISCLOSURES: CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS. If you are a California resident, you shall also have the right to know the specific pieces of personal information that One Green Planet has about you; and to have One Green Planet delete said pieces of personal information at your request. If you are a California resident, you may prevent the transfer of personal information to any third-party for consideration by sending an email to Team@www.onegreenplanet.org. Requests to know, requests to delete, and follow-up correspondence to requests to opt out may be sent to Team@onegreenplanet.Org

6\. ADDITIONAL DISCLOSURES: EU RESIDENTS. If you are a resident of the EU, you shall have the right to know the specific pieces of personal information that One Green Planet has about you; and to have One Green Planet correct, update, and/or delete said pieces of personal information at your request. Requests to know, correct, update, and/or delete, may be sent to Team@onegreenplanet.org

**Security**

We maintain safeguards to help protect the security, integrity and privacy of the personally-identifiable information within our control. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to protect your information, please be advised that we assume no responsibility or liability for disclosure of your information due to errors in transmission, unauthorized third-party access or other causes beyond our control.

**Third party links**

We do not control the data collection policies of any website linked to the OneGreenPlanet.org site. If you click on a link or an advertisement, the privacy policy of the website that you link to will govern the collection and use of your information by that website’s operators.  These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites with respect to their use of your information or otherwise. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**Collection of Information from Minors**

The OneGreenPlanet.org site is directed to, and intended for use by, adults only. We do not knowingly collect personally-identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personally identifiable information from a user under the age of thirteen, we will delete such information from our records.

**Acceptance of Privacy Policy**

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through OneGreenPlanet.org and not to information collected offline or via other means. When you use the OneGreenPlanet.org site, you are accepting the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, and we will have the right to use your information as described in this Privacy Policy.  If you do not agree to have your information used in any of the ways described in this Privacy Policy, you must discontinue use of the OneGreenPlanet.org Site. We may update this privacy policy at any time to reflect changes in our practices and service offerings. If we modify this privacy policy, we will update the “Effective Date.” Your continued use of the OneGreenPlanet.or Site after a change in the Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of those changes.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [team@www.onegreenplanet.org](mailto:team@www.onegreenplanet.org)

_Last Updated: February 23, 2023_

### Share this:
